Mike Honel N. Tresuelo

Address: Block 8 lot 15 Rivera Homes Subd. Majada out Calamba Laguna (4029)

Birth date: September 3, 1985

Marital Status: Married No. of Children: 1 Phone #: 09127711773

Email: mikehoneltresuelo.10@gmail.com



OBJECTIVE

Electro mechanical Technician with experience in Industrial Automation. In possession of hands on experience in machine troubleshooting both electrical and mechanical. A highly motivated individual and 100 % committed to face new challenges to develop his professional skills

SKILLS

- Electrical and Mechanical Assembly
- Electrical Control Panel Wiring
- Counter checking of Bill of materials
- Pneumatic Installation
- Dexterity
- Problem Solving Skill
- Analytical skill
- Can Speak and understand English

WORKING EXPERIENCE

TECHNICIAN (January 2017 - PRESENT) Key Automation unit inc.

149 East Main Avenue LOOP phase 6-C Laguna Technopark, Binan, Laguna, Philippines

- Install, maintain, and replace automation systems at Key points in the production process.
- Troubleshoot non-functioning components including Servos, Sensors, and control components.
- Log equipment usage, parts replacement, and scheduled maintenance to ensure maximum functionality.
- Periodically report to leadership regarding automation capabilities and status.
- Supporting new machine builds, Installation and modification.
- Suggesting and implementing improvements to manufacturing processes information and procedures.
- Developing Controls, Drawings and design concepts.

Electrical Technician(Sept. 2015 - March 2016) International Ductile Iron pipes co. Ltd. (KSA)

- Repair and replace defective components in motors, generators, controllers, storage batteries, switchboards, conductors, switches and varied electrical fixtures.
- Install, maintain and repair electrical, electro mechanical and electronic parts of machinery and equipment's.
- Perform defensive repair and preservation of field, plant and shop for electronic and electrical systems, equipment and devices.
- Test Solid State circuitry to determine defective components in analog and digital equipment along with defective parts replacement.
- Evaluate electrical as well as operational problems.

Technician(April 2010 - July 2015) Nidec Philippines Corp.

Laguna Technopark, Binan, Laguna

- Provide assistance to Assemble, test and maintain company equipment.
- Analyze root causes of equipment failures and propose corrective actions.
- Perform regular inspections to identify and correct equipment malfunctions, repairs and replacements.
- Read and understand Technical manuals for equipment operations and maintenance.
- Adhere to company policies and safety regulations.
- Develop preventive maintenance procedures to avoid equipment failures.
- Maintain the facility clean and safe.
- Clean and lubricate equipment on regular basis.
- Propose improvements to enhance equipments performance and reliability.
- Develop cost reduction initiatives by effective utilization of materials and resources.o

TRAINING AND SEMINAR

Keyence Vision System

EDUCATION

CARLOS HILADO MEMORIAL STATE COLLEGE

Bachelor of Science Industrial Technology Refrigeration and Air conditioning

Graduate SY: 2008-2009

EMILIANO LIZARES NATIONAL HIGH SCHOOL

Graduate SY: 2001 - 2002

ASUNCION LIZARES ELEMENTARY SCHOOL

Graduate SY: 1997 - 1998

CHARACTER REFERENCES

Domingo Ballecer	Jason Senoron	Engr. Sherialyne Gay Gutierrez
Sr. PLC Programmer	PLC Programmer	Process Engineer
Key Automation unit inc.	Key Automation unit inc.	Key Automation unit inc.
(+63) 9155375141	(+63) 9123697597	(+63) 9496693796